<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vasu Jain</title>
    <link>https://vasujain.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vasu Jain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:52:52 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vasujain.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Key Podcast Takeaways   Wisdom From CTO Subhash Choudhary</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/posts/key-podcast-takeaways---wisdom-from-cto-subhash-choudhary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:52:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/posts/key-podcast-takeaways---wisdom-from-cto-subhash-choudhary/</guid>
      <description>Found this great podcast of Subhash Choudhary, CTO, Dukaan and his life journey. It was so entertaining that I watched the whole 3-hour podcast in one sitting. It was packed with knowledge, life experiences and insights. I thought of summarizing my leanings from this podcast into a small blog post. So, here are some of the key takeaways from this gem of a podcast -&#xA;Be a Technologist first then a Businessman We should never open a startup if we want to have a luxurious life or we want to get insanely rich, we will most likely lose motivation and fail.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robosafe - Wireless Controlled Locker With Multi Factor Authentication</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/projects/robosafe---wireless-controlled-locker-with-multi-factor-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:33:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/projects/robosafe---wireless-controlled-locker-with-multi-factor-authentication/</guid>
      <description>A versatile wireless controlled locker system built using an Arduino Mega. It offers seamless unlocking through various methods including App control, RFID card, Fingerprint.&#xA;Features 🔒 Wireless Control: Unlock and access the locker remotely using a dedicated mobile app. 📱 Multi-factor Authentication: RFID Card: Swipe an authorized RFID card for quick access. 💳 Fingerprint: Unlock using biometric authentication for added security. 👆 Arduino Mega: Powered by the reliable Arduino Mega platform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MrDataAnalyst   Interactive Data Analysis Tool</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/projects/mrdataanalyst---interactive-data-analysis-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:33:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/projects/mrdataanalyst---interactive-data-analysis-tool/</guid>
      <description>An interactive data analysis tool that empowers users to input data, perform various data manipulation tasks, and visualize insights effortlessly. Built using Python&amp;rsquo;s Pandas, NumPy, and Matplotlib libraries, this tool is designed to simplify data analysis tasks.&#xA;Features 📊 Data Aggregation: Summarize and aggregate data based on specified criteria. 📈 Data Sorting: Arrange data in ascending or descending order for better understanding. 🔍 Data Pivoting: Transform data into pivot tables for multidimensional analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CBSE Results 2023 - Automated CBSE Result Scraper</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/projects/cbse-results-2023---automated-cbse-result-scraper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:28:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/projects/cbse-results-2023---automated-cbse-result-scraper/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I created a Python script built using Selenium to scrape scorecards from the CBSE Results Digilocker website. It can retrieve scorecards for all 12th-grade students in a school.&#xA;Features 📄 Automated Scraper: Retrieve scorecards for all 12th-grade students without manual effort. 🔄 Smart Scraping: Utilize Selenium for efficient and accurate data extraction. 🤖 Comprehensive Data: Obtain detailed scorecards from the CBSE Results Digilocker. 🎓 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OnePaceStremioV2 - Dynamic Stremio Addon for One Pace</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/projects/onepacestremiov2---dynamic-stremio-addon-for-one-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 15:26:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/projects/onepacestremiov2---dynamic-stremio-addon-for-one-pace/</guid>
      <description>A Dynamic Stremio addon written in JavaScript using Stremio SDK that provides a better way to watch One Pace on Stremio. It uses data from One Pace obtained through a GraphQL query.&#xA;Features 📺 Dynamic Stremio Addon: Enhance your Stremio experience with One Pace content. 🎬 Better Viewing: Enjoy One Pace content seamlessly on Stremio. 🚀 GraphQL Integration: Fetch One Pace data using GraphQL queries. 🔍 Tech Stack 🛠️ Programming: JavaScript Stremio SDK: Stremio addon development using the Stremio SDK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUR   the Reason I Switched From Debian 12 to Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/posts/aur---the-reason-i-switched-from-debian-12-to-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:15:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/posts/aur---the-reason-i-switched-from-debian-12-to-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Linux-based operating systems for the past couple of years now. I installed Linux Mint on my 6th gen i3 laptop to get better performance, and immediately fallen love with the command line. I love the fact we can control our whole system through certain sets of commands. I like the idea of installing an app through apt install directly and not having to go to that app website to first download an installer and click next multiple times to install an application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How JavaScript Execute Code</title>
      <link>https://vasujain.me/posts/how-javascript-execute-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:08:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasujain.me/posts/how-javascript-execute-code/</guid>
      <description>{} - This is our Global Execution Context (this)&#xA;Note: Global Execution Context is different in various environment like Node, Browser, Bun, etc.&#xA;It is a window object in browser and a empty object in a runtime like Nodejs.&#xA;Types of Execution Contexts There are mainly three types of global execution contexts:&#xA;Global Execution Context Functional Execution Context Eval Execution Context (Good to Know, mainly used in mongoose) How JS code is Executed?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
